Whoa!
Hi, everyone.
Thank you for coming.
This is a special talk from my colleague James Moss.
We work together at Tessl.
James is a member of technical staff, which means he's
a software engineer with a superiority complex.
Just kidding. I have been liking this.
Eventually we'll all just be employees and I look forward
to that time personally.
So James is going to be talking about a problem
that I would be surprised if you haven't encountered yourself.
Everyone in a team kind of uses agents a little bit differently.
James is going to talk about
some of the tension points when your disparate agent workflows
come together to try and work on the same piece of software.
So with that, over to James.
Thank you very much, Macy.
Hello everyone.
Hope you guys are enjoying AI native Dev Con so far.
Hopefully you have a little bit of a break. Have some coffee.
Brains warming up.
You're starting to feel a bit more engaged.
So a little bit about me.
My name is James Moss.
I've spent probably more than two decades working
in the industry across the stack, doing lots of different things.
Right now, I'm a software engineer.
Sorry, I mean, member of technical staff at Tessl, where I work on our registry
product, amongst many other things, as you do at startups.
So using skills to pay the bills.
If you didn't read the abstract
and you just read the title of the talk and you came and you thought
today I was going to be sharing a get rich quick scheme.
Here it is.
Maybe it works, maybe it doesn't.
You're probably going to be disappointed in the rest of the talk.
They've got to give you today.
Maybe you'll take away some priceless little nuggets that you can take home
and use yourself instead of this crazy, this crazy skill.
So yeah, we're going to talk about
adoption and management of skills within the enterprise, right.
So there's quite a different challenge to using skills within a personal vibe
coded project and requires a different set of practices.
So plan for today we're going to cover three things.
Skill sprawl,
which I'll talk about shortly, which you might have heard of before.
Skills or software.
So building on some of the things that guy was talking about this morning
and his keynote, and then a small piece at the end
around the context development lifecycle.
So let's kick off talking about skill sprawl.
First of all, maybe a term you haven't heard before.
If you think about skills
and authoring them, the barrier to entry is super low, right?
They're mostly just text files.
Sometimes you might put a couple of scripts in there with them.
It's super easy to add your own new ones or install third party ones from GitHub.
They're also pretty powerful as well, right?
Like, it's very easy to write a small amount of text and influence
how the agents works in quite a powerful way.
And so because of this, teams are facing this kind of
Cambrian explosion of skills within their organizations.
Guy mentioned in his slides this morning, we have 2 million
plus skills across GitHub, across 44,000 repos.
That's an insane amount.
That's obviously just the public ones as well.
I'm sure it's even higher in terms of internal private repos
and private skills as well.
So yeah, we're seeing skills spread across lots of different locations.
So and GitHub, as I mentioned, across things like Claude Marketplaces
and also on developers, local machines as well.
Right.
It's hard to get visibility around where skills are being used.
And if you can't track that,
then you can't measure that and you can't improve things. Right?
So this is a real problem right now that we're hearing from customers.
I collected some quotes that I want to kind of just quickly go through
with everyone here just to kind of outline this problem, right.
First up, we have a plethora of skills distributed across so many repositories
that's become incredibly difficult and almost impossible to get your head
wrapped around.
How to unify, centralize, and properly distribute skills across all teams.
So the from a lead architect and AI services company a couple more.
It's a free fall right now.
For the most part everyone's been doing their own thing.
It's the Wild West, right?
Another couple of engineers here, right?
These are experienced folk from the industry, from companies
you definitely heard of.
And this is an industry wide problem right now.
So a quick show of hands.
Who here kind of agrees with these statements?
Who here doesn't have a clear picture of every skill in use across your team?
Amazing.
Lots of hands.
I was worried no one was going to say this in my talk was falling on deaf ears.
So yeah, hopefully lots of you are recognizing this problem already
and you're facing the pain of that already, right?
So how does this sprawl manifest actually,
and impact humans and the agents that we're instructing.
So there's a couple of different failure modes that we're seeing.
The first one is overlap.
So this is where you might have multiple teams all building the same thing
in isolation, without realizing each team might have built their own version
of the skill. It might achieve the same thing.
You might have
generally the same outcomes, but it's done in a different way, right?
And you're having multiple kind of wasted effort there.
So that's overlap.
Next up we often see drift.
So this is where newer skills are shipping.
And teams aren't keeping up with those newer versions.
And a good example here recently is Matt Pocock.
Hopefully you've all heard of him.
He's great educator, published a bunch of great skills.
He has a grill me skill.
That's where you kind of do an interview with the agent and you kind of
get a shared understanding.
He recently published a newer version of that grill school called grill
with docs, which kind of expands on it and adds a lot more detail to it.
I'm sure there's lots of folks that don't realize that that's been released, right?
And they're still using that order version and haven't updated.
So that's drift.
We also have problems around activation or a lack of activation, right.
Lots of people are producing these skills.
Are they being used by the agents.
Are they being used by humans.
There's no real way to to understand that
and know that right now you probably don't have that visibility yet.
So Guy mentioned this in his talk as well.
This morning.
You might have a skill that describes some code or a code base, or a process
or even a workflow, and those two things can quickly go out of sync
so your skill never gets updated. Things change.
And in those instances, having an outdated skill can often
be just as bad as having no skill at all.
Right?
Next up is overloading
the last one here, and this is one that you might not be aware of.
This is having too many skills in a single repository.
So right now you might not know, but there is actually a limit
to the amount of skills you can have with most coding agents,
often expressed as a percentage of the context window.
So if we think about our skills, the name and the description gets injected
into the start of every context window, as the agent knows about those skills
and knows when to use them, makes decision about activating them.
What can happen here is undefined.
Most agents will truncate that description,
which means you end up in a situation where your skills might not be activated
because the description
has been shortened, and key bits of information
that the model kind of needs to know about to be able to to invoke that skill
and not there anymore. Right.
So these are the the major failure modes that we're seeing.
So we set out to detect and actually solve these problems for our customers.
And so we've built a skills of entry right.
We connect to your GitHub org.
We pull in all the skills we find across all your repos.
We let you kind of drill into how they're being used.
So you can break it down by repo.
You can break it down by skill.
You can see those first party skills, those third party skills.
You can see token usage on those skills.
And we are also able to surface those findings as well that it talks about.
So that previous slide with those different failure modes
we're able to find those surfaced them to you produce a report
and then you can go and fix that and decide what you want to do.
We're also able to lean on our public registry.
And if we're finding a third party
skill that you're using within, there will also surface any reviews
or eval scores or security scans that we've also done on that skill.
This is currently in private beta.
It's very, very new.
If you're interested, come and find me.
I'm working on the Tessl booth for the rest of the day.
I'm more than happy to chat and give you a quick demo.
Run you through this if you're having the same problems as most people seem to be.
So quick recap on Sproule.
Let's go.
Right.
We need to start measuring how we're actually using skills
across our organization.
And we need to track that over time
so that we can improve that and resolve those issues.
So that's a recap.
Next up I want to talk about skills and software.
So this is kind of building on a lot of the things
that Guy talked about this morning.
I want to give you some actionable things that you can take away and use
within your own teams and your own organizations today.
So I'm not going to go into lots of detail
about what makes an individual skill work.
Hopefully many of you in here are already familiar with that.
There's lots of resources on there, but I want to talk about the kind of ecosystem
of exists around skills.
Before we dive into that, I want to talk about the agent equation.
Right.
So if we think about it, an agent is a function of the model,
the harness and the context. Right.
Changing any one of these three pieces has an impact
on how the agent works and its output, and the quality of its output.
Right.
Most of the time, we're probably not going to change the model of the harness
so much that's harder to do.
Or maybe we're kind of tied into using a certain model
or a certain harness within the organization we're working in.
And so context is effectively the best lever
that we can pull to affect the outcome of the agent here.
And it has a pretty big impact as well.
Right. I'm sure most of you are familiar with this, right.
You can do a lot in terms of where you're doing instructions and the skills you use
and the prompting you use, and the kind of hooks you have set up.
So within context, skills, again,
feel like an important kind of powerful piece
because they can encode business or domain specific logic
and that the model won't have been trained on.
So you can give the model that knowledge that it won't otherwise know about.
So given all of this thinking about this, what can we do
to make skills as effective as possible?
So first one nice and easy.
Hopefully you're already doing this.
Don't write monolithic skills right.
Don't write huge epic skills.
Think about decomposing breaking skills down into smaller pieces.
Most agent coding tools support the use of plugins.
If you're
not familiar with plugins, plugin is just a group of context
related together that can be installed into your agent.
Coding tools.
Agents can then pick and choose which parts of the plugins they want to use.
Because you're breaking down your skill into smaller ones,
you can use descriptions for each of those individual pieces,
and so the agent is more likely to activate
those individually, rather than trying to stuff a load of
kind of keywords into a bigger description of a larger skill.
And you can also end up building
kind of pretty complex, interconnected skills as well.
So I mentioned this morning that skills can call skills.
And so you can have one skill that is maybe invoked by a human
that sets up the agent to call a bunch of other skills.
An example of that recently is we built a UI skill, a test
which enabled us to build user interfaces in the browser.
So we would take a Figma design.
We would feed that into one skill that was able to break that Figma design
down into its various components, and then hand that off to somebody
using other skills to implement those.
So we had a specific skill for building kind of low level components like buttons,
a separate one for building sort of high level components,
things like pages, and another one for those things in the middle,
things like forms that perhaps compose buttons, text inputs, that kind of thing.
And so the agent was able to do all of these.
But the powerful part about breaking them apart
is that me as a human, I could go in
and if I wanted to just build a small widget, I could just invoke the
that kind of low level, sort of like button level skill that describes
how to build sort of generic components if you wanted to.
So that's decompose extend.
So skills are just text right.
And they get ventured into your repo as well.
So you have a copy of a bunch of all these skills.
Very tempting to just edit them directly.
You've got some issue with the way the agent is acting
after using your skill.
I'll just edit that right in the git repo. Right.
Don't. Please don't do that.
Your teammates won't like you.
What you want to do here is extend third party skills.
So let's say you've got a great code review skill that you like the look of,
but it's not tailored to the technology stack
you're using or the best practices you have employed in your company.
Write your own first party skill that invokes that skill.
Agents have a pretty good understanding of kind of intent here, and what needs to
sort of override each piece.
And they can fill in the blank. So extend.
And then lastly, thinking back to our kind of see us 101,
if folks remember that thinking about the solid principles
s as a single responsibility principle, it's important for skills to write.
So don't overload that skill.
Again, closely coupled to decomposition.
Next up, avoid global skills.
So what do we mean by this right.
This is the works on my machine problem skills that are installed
on a developers machine but live outside of the repo right.
So if a skill lives on someone's local config rather than in the repo,
the agent sorry, the agent's behavior depends on who's running it.
Two different people
run the same task against the same code base and get very different output,
because one has the skill and the other one doesn't,
or it has a different version of it, right?
Horrible to debug trying to work out what's happened, right?
The skill isn't in the diff.
The use of the skill isn't in the diff.
It's not in the review, it's not in CI.
And the divergence kind of has no paper trail here.
It's really hard to track down.
The fix here is the same instinct is committing
kind of your log file and traditional code packages.
Skills that affect output
should be version controlled alongside the thing that they're acting on.
So not floating around in user's home directory.
A colleague recently attended a small forum
with Boris Cherny, creator of Claude Code, and he had this to say.
So we ban any local setup.
All agent workflow improvements, hooks, skills, etc.
must be checked into the repo for everyone.
So if Boris is doing it, he's following my guidelines already.
So amazing work Boris.
Next up is automated
skill reviews, so I don't think you, or probably
your agent wouldn't commit code without running it through a linter.
We often ask agents for write tests for us for a kind of a single module of code.
Skill review is kind of similar to these two processes, right?
The quick to run, you can run them locally after making changes
to the contents of your skill to kind of get that quick feedback loop.
You can also run them in CI as well to kind of gate quality regressions
and sort of failed build if skills don't meet that
certain level here in the screenshot, hopefully it's not too small.
You can see I've run the skill review on the skill that I shared at the start.
So lots of green ticks is a valid skill.
The line count is not too long, the front matter is valid or good.
Our skill review also has another piece to it
which uses an LLM as a judge, which is not so happy.
It's given me a score of 20% here saying that I definitely shouldn't.
It's got inherently dangerous financial operations.
So, you know, we have a certain level of gating for skills with Tessl.
This one definitely isn't getting published.
It's not getting pastor.
Next up, publish to a registry.
So right now I imagine most of you are here are probably loading your skills
directly from repos on GitHub, sort of via the Claude marketplace,
or perhaps using something like NP Skills command.
And that's fine.
That's the path of least resistance right now, but the registry adds a lot more.
On top right.
You have this one source of truth.
Everyone's pulling the same version of the skill, the same pin version.
Right now, there's a kind of a explosion of skills on GitHub
that are forks, right?
So someone's forked a skill.
It's from a different place.
They've changed something slightly.
It's very easy to end up with two skills and name the same thing.
Look like they do the same thing, but they're not in fact the same skill.
So registry also allows you to stay current safely
to know when there's updates, review diffs, rollback, that kind of thing.
Discoverability is a big piece.
If we think about think back to the skill.
Sprawl. Overlap is a big concern.
You know, having a centralized registry where all this stuff is
can help people find those skills and not write their own, as well
as kind of maybe promoting skills to you that you would want to use.
And lastly, there's an interesting one that we're hearing from some customers
as they're rolling out skills to non-tech folks,
their skills are living inside private GitHub repos,
and they have to provision a GitHub seat for those non-technical users.
So even though they're not using any of the features of GitHub,
they're having to pay however many dollars a month right now for users
to be able to access those skills in those private repos.
And so putting putting a registry in front of where your source code lives
helps negate that kind of issue.
The registry is also a great enforcement point, right?
It gives you a surface to be able to put in place governance and enforce
company policies, kind of examples of those things like approved skills only.
Perhaps you allow all your first party skills,
but only a small subset of third party skills, because the kind of risk profile
within your company, similar piece around security
and kind of bad actors at sneak we do security scans.
Sorry, that's all we use. Sneak.
We partner with sneak to do
security scans of all the things that blend it to the registry.
Right. And so you might want to enforce that.
Only the highest level security checks pass before skills can be installed.
And then finally the minimum release age. Right?
I think this is definitely quite personal right now.
For those that are not aware, you can you can set a minimum release age
of say a few days.
And any packages newer than that can't be installed.
This is especially pertinent for us.
Tessl last month is just like 3 or 4 weeks ago we had the mini Shiloh
tech, which affected a bunch of packages that we depend on.
We're big npm stack fans at Tessl,
and the malware here was notable
because it was basically a spy chain attack, but it was notable
because it had a level of persistence where it added a global clawed code
hook to your machine to try and keep it self installed on the user's machine.
So another good reason not to use any kind of global state for your skills.
We weren't affected by this because in our node package manager
we have a release age of a few days.
The stack team that were found this issue pretty quickly and cleaned it up.
So there's no way any devs could have installed that.
This is not such a big thing right now in terms of some of the skills on registry,
I think OpenClaw, maybe it's definitely an issue right now.
Guy mentioned this morning and it was at 20% of all the skills.
And there are malicious.
We're going to see that expanding into other registries other skills as well.
And it's not long before I'm sure we'll see as chain issue
if you're loading it straight from GitHub, what's in the way what stands between
that code being on GitHub
and being compromised and being installed into your machine, versus having
something like a registry in the middle that is able to kind of save you that.
Next up, don't look your skills to one agent.
I grabbed a screenshot from the skills repo.
Take a look at the project paths.
How many are there there? I don't know, there's so many.
This is also only up to K as well, which is what
the 11th list or the alphabet?
There's many, many more, right?
Some there's some good people that are using the agents
kind of pattern for putting their skills inside.
But this is crazy, right.
And so if we think about the agents
we're using in six months might look nothing like today's right.
The cost of tokens is going up, Openweight models are getting more and more
kind of traction, and you don't want to be just tied into one coding agent, right?
Skills are effectively your durable asset.
The agent is just the runtime.
You want to keep them portable, and you don't want to have
to rewrite your investment every time the landscape shifts.
Or you want to do experiments with new tooling, right?
Also, why registry matters as well, especially a package manager.
It can abstract away a lot of this pain
of having to put these things in different places.
You just write it once,
and then the manager
will take care of installing it into whatever agent you're using.
Next up,
making context a team asset, not just a personal setup.
Keeping things dry.
So one source of truth having shared ownership,
not letting one person or one team own everything super important.
Making things safe to contribute, right?
If people feel like a skill is highly dependent upon by many,
many others in the company, they might not feel safe to contribute to.
So putting in place those kind of CI checks I mentioned
and gating and creating a safe space where they can edit
skills and create skills without feeling they're going to break
the kind of internal ecosystem for, for many folks, super important.
I'm going to touch on evals, finally measuring with evals.
So I like to think of evals as a bit of an experiment and treating
skill success as a measurement, sorry, as an experiment.
And if you can't measure it again, you can't improve it.
I found a couple of funding posts from Reddit and LinkedIn here.
We've got a claim that they built a clawed skill that can reduce,
stops overthinking, and cuts token usage by 60 to 80%, right?
It seems pretty crazy.
I want Claude to think more, not less.
44% increase in coding accuracy, right?
Four rules from capacity added to your Claude, MD
and coding accuracy jumped from 65 to to 94%.
I don't really know what coding actually means, but it was great to see.
Big uptick this one 20,000 tokens added to every prompt, right?
This guy here is saying that he's got this magic prompt that kills
90% of production bugs before they're written, right.
Is it a bug?
If it never existed, I don't know.
There's some sort of like Heisenberg there. Very strange.
All these kind of claims make me think about this awesome quote
from Adam Savage of MythBusters fame.
Hopefully you know who he is.
I think this quote now, the difference
between screwing around and science is writing it
down is kind of more important than ever, and the sort of vibes based world
that that we're living in.
So to me is a bit like writing it down.
If we go back to the agent equation, Evals let you change any part of it,
right?
The model, the harness, the context and measure actually happens to the output.
You can run evals against a single skill or multiple skills,
and you can run them against a real code base to see what holds up
and what breaks right.
They also answer questions that might be difficult to answer
by doing kind of manual testing.
So things like will this change make the skill worse?
Swapping different models out many different models.
Does the skills to work. Do you even need this skill?
Has the agent
sorry, has the model just got better and you no longer need to worry about
kind of documenting some of these processes that you are within skills.
So quick recap on skills and software decompose.
Do your reviews, make sure you implement a registry and have policies around that
that kind of fit your company and the things that you care about.
Team ownership make it safe for everyone to contribute.
And then finally using evals to be able to measure
that express success with experiments.
So lastly, I want to
touch on the context of element lifecycle.
So everything you do to keep code
healthy already has a direct equivalent for context, right?
You probably just haven't really been doing it yet.
If you think about skill reviews, they're like linting and unit tests.
Evil is a bit more like end to end tests.
Code registries are kind of like, sorry, context rotaries, like code registries.
And when it comes to authoring skills, the same reflexes that you apply
with code also apply to context and skills, right?
You compose things together, you avoid global state.
All of those things matter.
And lastly, same things with human factors for code, right?
We don't have siloed knowledge.
Avoid that kind of bus factor.
So all those same things apply.
I want to leave you guys on a bit of a story.
When you think back to 2005, if you were able to remember that
if you're slightly old enough to remember it, Myspace was in its heyday.
Mr. Brightside by The Killers was topping the charts.
It's pretty phone.
There's no iPhone is pre GitHub, pre containers, pre DevOps.
I was a fresh face developer out of university writing PHP
at my very first gig.
At that time PHP had no package manager, right?
It was seven years before composer came around
and so if we wanted to install things we'd go over to SourceForge, we'd
download a zip, we'd extract that vendor that into our code base.
We'd never do any kind of security review.
Right. We're not looking at that code.
We're not thinking, hey, does this have a vulnerability in it?
We're just like, cool, this is a date library we want to have in our code.
Right.
The, the, the there was no semantic versioning that hadn't been invented yet.
It was whatever the author's kind of whim was to updating that deployment
kind of made me wince a little bit, thinking, thinking about deployment.
So we used to use FTP and we would,
we would copy files across on FTP
into straight into production, which it's just mad to me now.
We weren't total monsters.
We used SftP.
Right.
So this is crazy, right?
Like we would never dare to do any of this kind of stuff now.
And it took the industry about ten years to sort of fix all of this, right?
We invented or at least for PHP.
We invented a package manager.
We have we had lock files, registry, CI test,
dependency scanning, signed releases, all this stuff.
Right. All this stuff that we now kind of take for granted.
You'd never imagine dragging a file into prod anymore, hopefully.
Right.
So we would never do any of those outdated practices anymore,
but it does feel like we are doing them a bit with skills and contexts right now.
Like in some of the ways we're working
where we're skipping package managers, we are suing directly from the source
and we're not we don't have these kind of CI things up in place.
Right.
So the good news is we already know how the story ends, right?
We don't have to spend another
ten years coming up with these processes and rediscovering those.
We can apply what we've learned with the SDLC to the CDC, right.
We just have to make sure we're not making the same mistakes again.
Cool.
Thanks.
James.
Yes, we have four minutes for questions.
Does anyone have any question for James?
Thank you.
So I've been using the test registry and I was curious about the
now you're migrating everything plugins I understand from skills.
That's right.
And so if I have multiple skills
do I have to package them into a plugin.
Should I keep them separate?
And what's the suggestion here?
The classic answer it depends.
It depends you we I think we are planning
on allowing you
to upload individual skills,
even though we're kind of focusing on plugins right now.
It comes down to your needs, right?
Like my example there,
I was talking about a bunch of skills that are related
and so that makes sense to package to them.
You might want to also package a bunch of kind of related plugins
that are broader.
Perhaps you have a bunch of plugins that everyone uses, right?
Almost like a standard library for for skills across your company,
and you want everyone to install that, and you want to just give them one
dependency that they can install and keep things up to date.
So yeah, as I say, it depends.
It depends on your use case.
We want to support both ways.
Whatever's kind of flexible for yourself..
Because we have a very aggressive warning from the planning now from the client.
You have to move the planning.
Any more.
I I'd love to hear more on the kind of
how you share this with non-technical people in the company
because like permitting bats, if you're using JIRA
and you're updating tickets and using skills to help with that,
and you want to share that with the other half of the business.
Yeah.
How do you do that?
This is a huge problem right now.
Like this is probably again,
one of the bigger, bigger questions we're hearing from customers.
I don't think there's a good answer.
Expecting folks to start running CLI commands in the terminal
to build skills locally I think is going to be difficult.
Yeah, definitely don't have a good answer for that.
One is a real problem.
People don't.
Again, we don't want to be in the position where we are
passing things like zips and files around getting folks to install that.
I think what we'll probably end up having is some sort of GUI.
Imagine for most folks, and probably roots lie.
So I don't know. I'm not committing to that though.
Thanks for the talk. Who?
Excellent.
What do you think to APM as a solution for some of the problems
that you mentioned. Is great.
Yeah, I've played around with it a bit.
Very very good.
Definitely use APM if that's what you want to use.
For those that don't know,
it's package manager from it was started by one guy at Microsoft.
Now kind of come under an umbrella umbrella of the whole of Microsoft.
Yeah really good.
Definitely use it if you if you if that's going to work for you.
Anyone else. Yes.
Can you.
How do you recommend expressing dependencies
between skills and particularly skills that are not in the same package.
So if you have a kind of generic set and a specific set,
because there isn't a standard way, as I understood it at the moment, to to.
Relate that this is peer dependencies, it's something that I think everyone's
a bit scared to tackle.
Guy mentioned this morning again is keynote around
dependency management and resolution and what a pain that is.
I didn't work at snake.
There's lots of folks that didn't work at Sneaker
Tussle today have faced that pain and they understand that.
I think ultimately it comes down to maybe having something like peer dependencies.
I think we're also in a position where maybe there's
nothing better than that, right?
Like we're moving to more agent world peer dependencies and maybe an artifact
of this world where things had to be more predictable and deterministic.
And so maybe just the agent being able to look at the skill and say,
hey, I need to use this other skill by reading it.
I think that could also be a solution to that.
Thank you guys.
That's all we have time for.
But lucky for you, James will be easy to find.
If you want to chat with him.
He'll be at the Tessl booth today and tomorrow.
Yeah, I think both days. Yeah. Both days.
Chat to me? Yeah.
Come by and chat to James. Thank you all so much.
The next talk will be in exactly ten minutes.
1145 you'll get a preview of Stack Overflow for agents.
If that doesn't pique your curiosity, I don't know why you're here.
Thank you very much.
Thank you. Thank you very much.